<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.1.4">
			<file name="sources.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Heliana-s-Guide-to-Monster-Hunting/refs/heads/main/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Heliana's Guide to Monster Hunting" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_LT_SOURCE_HGTMH">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Heliana’s Guide to Monster Hunting is a collection of ideas.</strong></p><p> You are encouraged to use whichever pieces of this book you like and change the ones you don’t. If there is a DC that seems off, a name that doesn’t fit, or a quest hook that seems incongruous, then make it your own. Remember: if you’re all having fun, you’re doing it right.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">HGTMH</set>
			<set name="url">https://loottavern.com/product/helianas-guide-to-monster-hunting/</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Heliana-s-Guide-to-Monster-Hunting/refs/heads/main/BOO_Heliana.jpg</set>
			<set name="errata">https://loottavern.com/Heliana_Errata/Helianas_Guide_Errata_-_October_9th_2024_-_v1.0.pdf</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="LT" url="https://loottavern.com/">Loot Tavern</set>
			<set name="third-party">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Wrath of The Kaiju" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_LT_SOURCE_WOK">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>When geologists struggle to describe the processes by which geological phenomena may have come into existence, they often give a resigned shrug and utter the words ‘SNACK event’, short for ‘Situation Normal: A Kaiju event’. Within the Yokai Realms, this phrase has become shorthand for ‘No one knows how, but something immense has occurred’ and is often used to describe blunders such as adventurers reawakening sleeping death gods, failed ‘Fire Festivals’ on the Elemental Planes, or accidentally opening a massive portal to the Fey Planes.</p>
			<p>But this phrase is based on fact. Kaiju change the world. Their footsteps create depressions that form lakes, the errant swipe of a tail can decapitate a mountain, and their morning yawn can cause landslides. They are products of nature and magic, bound by destiny to be reborn for as long as there is a world for them to exist in. All we can do is make the most of the time when they’re not around.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">WOK</set>
			<set name="url">https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/dndshorts/ryokos-guide-to-the-yokai-realms-a-5e-tome/faqs</set>
			<set name="image">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Heliana-s-Guide-to-Monster-Hunting/refs/heads/main/WOK.jpg</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="LT" url="https://loottavern.com/">Loot Tavern</set>
			<set name="third-party">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
