<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>School of Biomancy</name>
		<source>Heliana's Guide to Monster Hunting</source>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="Wizard.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Heliana-s-Guide-to-Monster-Hunting/refs/heads/main/Classes/Wizard.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="School of Biomancy" type="Archetype" source="Heliana's Guide to Monster Hunting" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_SCHOOL_OF_BIOMANCY">
		<supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Practitioners of biomancy tend to have a growth mindset and an endless propensity for self-improvement. You likely bear symptoms of this continual desire to improve yourself: patches of scales, manes of peacock feathers, hawk’s eyes, adhesive palms, gills… the list is as long as there are ideas to try. Biomancers are masters of biomantically-enhanced surgery, transplanting specially-grown (or amputated) appendages onto other creatures.</p>
			<div element="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_BIOMANCY_SAVANT" />
			<div element="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_BIOSTIMULATION" />
			<div element="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_SELF_IMPROVEMENT" />
			<div element="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_SPELL_SPLITTER" />
			<div element="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_ENDOCRINE_OVERLOAD" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Practitioners of biomancy tend to have a growth mindset and an endless propensity for self-improvement.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_BIOMANCY_SAVANT" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_BIOSTIMULATION" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_SELF_IMPROVEMENT" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_SPELL_SPLITTER" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_ENDOCRINE_OVERLOAD" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Biomancy Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Heliana's Guide to Monster Hunting" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_BIOMANCY_SAVANT">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a biomancy spell into your spellbook is halved. In addition, you gain proficiency with surgeon’s tools, and the following spells are considered biomancy spells for you instead of their normal school.</p>
			<h5>Biomancy Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><i>false life, longstrider</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>alter self, darkvision, spider climb</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>haste, water breathing</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>4th</td><td><i>stoneskin</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>6th</td><td><i>flesh to stone</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><i>simulacrum</i></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><i>shapechange</i></td></tr>
			</table>
			<p class="indent">*See page 494 - 495 for lists of spells that can be from the school of biomancy.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The gold and time you must spend to copy a biomancy spell into your spellbook is halved. In addition, you gain proficiency with surgeon’s tools, and the following spells are considered biomancy spells for you instead of their normal school.</description>
		</sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Wizard" extend="true">
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_AID</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAL</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEAL</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_REGENERATE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY</extend>
        </spellcasting>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SURGEONS_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Biostimulation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Heliana's Guide to Monster Hunting" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_BIOSTIMULATION">
		<description>
			<p>You learn to channel biomantic magic into your cells, restoring your vitality. When you use a spell slot to cast a biomancy spell of 1st level or higher, you can simultaneously redirect a strand of the spell’s magic to energise and repair you or your target’s body. You or your target (your choice) regains a number of hit points equal to twice the spell’s level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use a spell slot to cast a biomancy spell of 1st level or higher, you can simultaneously redirect a strand of the spell’s magic to energise and repair you or your target’s body. You or your target (your choice) regains a number of hit points equal to twice the spell’s level.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Self Improvement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Heliana's Guide to Monster Hunting" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_SELF_IMPROVEMENT">
		<description>
			<p>You can perform minor surgery on your body, improving yourself in a very literal sense. Over the course of 1 hour (which can be done during a rest), you can enhance yourself with one bio-magical improvement, choosing from the following options:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Amphibisprings.</b> With enhanced quads and a ratcheting mechanism in your achilles, your jumping distance is tripled.</li>
				<li><b>Extra Appendage.</b> You gain a prehensile tail or an extra arm, allowing you to hold one more thing and conferring advantage on any ability checks you make to climb.</li>
				<li><b>Detachable Hand.</b> As an action, you can detach your hand and imbue it with biomantic magic. The hand follows the rules of the unseen servant spell, except it is not invisible and waits patiently if ever more than 60 feet away from you. If your hand is ever reduced to 0 hit points, it is destroyed, and you grow a new one over the course of a short or long rest.</li>
				<li><b>Firefly Skin.</b> You can cast the light cantrip at will with yourself as the target. As a bonus action, you can flash brightly for a moment; each creature within 5 feet of you that can see you must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or be blinded until the end of your next turn. After you use this bonus action, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</li>
				<li><b>Owl Eyes.</b> You gain darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</li>
				<li><b>Slime.</b> You exude slime; checks made to grapple you have disadvantage.</li>
				<li><b>Scales.</b> Your skin is covered in overlapping scales. You gain a +1 bonus to AC when you aren’t wearing armour.</li>
				<li><b>Spidersense.</b> You gain a 1d4 bonus to your initiative rolls.</li>
				<li><b>Talon.</b> One of your hands is replaced with a wicked giant hawk’s talon, a natural weapon that you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal slashing damage equal to 1d8 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike. If you are grappling a creature with this talon, you can automatically deal this damage to the grappled creature once on each of your turns as a bonus action.</li>
				<li><b>Third Leg.</b> Your speed increases by 10 feet and you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws made against effects that would knock you prone.</li>
				<li><b>Trimorphism.</b> You can cast the enlarge/reduce spell on yourself at will (no material components or concentration required).</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Your body has enough latent biomantic magic to sustain one improvement at a time. When you reach 10th and 14th level, you can sustain up to two and three improvements at a time, respectively. If you gain a new improvement while you have your maximum number of sustainable improvements active, you must choose one improvement to lose; this improvement withers away and ceases to function the moment you finish the surgery on your new improvement.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Over the course of 1 hour (which can be done during a rest), you can enhance yourself with one bio-magical improvement, choosing from the following options:&#13;
            • Amphibisprings. With enhanced quads and a ratcheting mechanism in your achilles, your jumping distance is tripled.&#13;
            • Extra Appendage. You gain a prehensile tail or an extra arm, allowing you to hold one more thing and conferring advantage on any ability checks you make to climb.&#13;
            • Detachable Hand. As an action, you can detach your hand and imbue it with biomantic magic. The hand follows the rules of the unseen servant spell, except it is not invisible and waits patiently if ever more than 60 feet away from you. If your hand is ever reduced to 0 hit points, it is destroyed, and you grow a new one over the course of a short or long rest.&#13;
            • Firefly Skin. You can cast the light cantrip at will with yourself as the target. As a bonus action, you can flash brightly for a moment; each creature within 5 feet of you that can see you must succeed on a DC {{self improvement:dc}} Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the end of your next turn. After you use this bonus action, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.&#13;
            • Owl Eyes. You gain darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.&#13;
            • Slime. You exude slime; checks made to grapple you have disadvantage.&#13;
            • Scales. Your skin is covered in overlapping scales. You gain a +1 bonus to AC when you aren’t wearing armour.&#13;
            • Spidersense. You gain a 1d4 bonus to your initiative rolls.&#13;
            • Talon. One of your hands is replaced with a wicked giant hawk’s talon, a natural weapon that you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal 1d8 + {{strength:modifier}} slashing damage, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike. If you are grappling a creature with this talon, you can automatically deal this damage to the grappled creature once on each of your turns as a bonus action.&#13;
            • Third Leg. Your speed increases by 10 feet and you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws made against effects that would knock you prone.&#13;
            • Trimorphism. You can cast the enlarge/reduce spell on yourself at will (no material components or concentration required).&#13;
            Your body has enough latent biomantic magic to sustain one improvement at a time. When you reach 10th and 14th level, you can sustain up to two and three improvements at a time, respectively. If you gain a new improvement while you have your maximum number of sustainable improvements active, you must choose one improvement to lose; this improvement withers away and ceases to function the moment you finish the surgery on your new improvement.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="self improvement:dc" value="8" />
            <stat name="self improvement:dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="self improvement:dc" value="intelligence:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Spell Splitter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Heliana's Guide to Monster Hunting" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_SPELL_SPLITTER">
		<description>
			<p>Your fiddling self-improvement has led to the ability to benefit from the magic you create. When you cast a wizard spell that targets only one creature and doesn’t have a range of self, you can choose to simultaneously target yourself with the same spell. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum once), regaining all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest" bonus="base">
			<description>When you cast a wizard spell that targets only one creature and doesn’t have a range of self, you can choose to simultaneously target yourself with the same spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Endocrine Overload" type="Archetype Feature" source="Heliana's Guide to Monster Hunting" id="ID_LT_HGTMH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_BIOMANCY_ENDOCRINE_OVERLOAD">
		<description>
			<p>Over the course of 1 hour (which can be done during a rest), you can craft a capsule of potent stimulants, choosing from either the Brutish or Swift archetypes, and embed it within your adrenal gland. With a slight tensing of your brain muscles, you can crack this capsule as a bonus action, stimulating your body. For the next minute, you gain the following benefits based on the archetype you chose:</p>
			<p><b>Brutish</b></p>
			<ul>
				<li>If you are smaller than Large, you become Large, and your weight increases proportionately. If you lack the room to become Large, your size doesn’t change.</li>
				<li>Your Strength score increases to match your Intelligence score if it isn’t already higher.</li>
				<li>You have advantage on Strength and Constitution checks and Strength and Constitution saving throws.</li>
				<li>You grow an appendage with which you can make melee weapon attacks. When you grow the weapon, you decide whether it deals bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage. You are proficient with this weapon and use your Strength modifier for attack and damage rolls. The weapon deals 2d10 damage.</li>
				<li>You can attack twice, instead of once, when you take the Attack action on your turn. You ignore this benefit if you already have a feature, like Extra Attack, that lets you attack more than once when you take the Attack action on your turn.</li>
				<li>You gain temporary hit points equal to twice your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 2) at the start of each of your turns.</li>
			</ul>
			<p><b>Swift</b></p>
			<ul>
				<li>Your Dexterity score increases to match your Intelligence score if it isn’t already higher.</li>
				<li>You have advantage on Dexterity checks and saving throws.</li>
				<li>Your cantrips with a casting time of 1 action have a casting time of 1 action or 1 bonus action.</li>
				<li>You gain the benefits of the haste spell, which can’t be dispelled:</li>
				<li>Your speed is doubled.</li>
				<li>You gain a +2 bonus to AC.</li>
				<li>You can take one additional action on each of your turns, which can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.</li>
			</ul>
			<p><b>Relapse.</b> When the minute elapses, you gain one level of exhaustion, and you can’t move or take actions until the end of your next turn, as a wave of lethargy sweeps over you. You must craft another capsule before you can use this feature again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Over the course of 1 hour (which can be done during a rest), you can craft a capsule of potent stimulants, choosing from either the Brutish or Swift archetypes, and embed it within your adrenal gland. With a slight tensing of your brain muscles, you can crack this capsule as a bonus action, stimulating your body. For the next minute, you gain the following benefits based on the archetype you chose:&#13;
            Brutish&#13;
            • If you are smaller than Large, you become Large, and your weight increases proportionately. If you lack the room to become Large, your size doesn’t change.&#13;
            • Your Strength score increases to match your Intelligence score if it isn’t already higher.&#13;
            • You have advantage on Strength and Constitution checks and Strength and Constitution saving throws.&#13;
            • You grow an appendage with which you can make melee weapon attacks. When you grow the weapon, you decide whether it deals bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage. You are proficient with this weapon: +{{brutish:attack}} to hit or deals 2d10 + {{strength:modifier}} damage.&#13;
            • You can attack twice, instead of once, when you take the Attack action on your turn. You ignore this benefit if you already have a feature, like Extra Attack, that lets you attack more than once when you take the Attack action on your turn.&#13;
            • You gain {{brutish:temp}} temporary hit points at the start of each of your turns.&#13;
            Swift&#13;
            • Your Dexterity score increases to match your Intelligence score if it isn’t already higher.&#13;
            • You have advantage on Dexterity checks and saving throws.&#13;
            • Your cantrips with a casting time of 1 action have a casting time of 1 action or 1 bonus action.&#13;
            • You gain the benefits of the haste spell, which can’t be dispelled:&#13;
            • Your speed is doubled.&#13;
            • You gain a +2 bonus to AC.&#13;
            • You can take one additional action on each of your turns, which can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action.&#13;
            Relapse. When the minute elapses, you gain one level of exhaustion, and you can’t move or take actions until the end of your next turn, as a wave of lethargy sweeps over you. You must craft another capsule before you can use this feature again.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="brutish:attack" value="strength:modifier" />
            <stat name="brutish:attack" value="proficiency" />

            <stat name="brutish:temp" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="2"/>
            <stat name="brutish:temp" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="2"/>
        </rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Append Biomancy school-->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLESH_TO_STONE">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAL">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEAL">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REGENERATE">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPECHANGE">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SIMULACRUM">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING">
        <supports>Biomancy</supports>
    </append>
</elements>